Hello everyone,
I am Wang Jingkun,
I will introduce you to the statistical learning
method today. Computers and networks have been integrated
into people's daily work and life,
and become indispensable assistants and partners. The
rapid development of computers and networks
has completely changed people's learning and lifestyle.
Intelligentization
is a major goal of computer research and
development. Practices in
recent decades have shown that statistical
learning methods are the most effective means of
achieving this goal,
although it still has certain limitations. The author
has been engaged in the research of various intelligent
processing of text data using statistical learning
methods.