Computer is our daily necessities. Our
daily life is inseparable from the computer.
Whether you
are using the computer directly or not, you are using
the computer intentionally or unintentionally,
or using the computer to provide you with
services,
such as you go. Bank withdrawal ATM is a computer,
you withdraw
money on the counter, the
bank’s resources are also used by the computer.
When we use a computer, we all need to
use the software already on the computer. For
example, if
you are using a mobile phone, of
course, we must first say that the mobile phone is
also a
computer. When we want to use the
mobile phone, what we want is where to go. An app
instead of saying that we have to write an app
ourselves
Of course, if you searched all the
markets,
you can't find the APP you want. Maybe
you have to write one yourself at this
time.
If you have a special request on the computer,
you
want to do a special thing, you
can't find the right software,
maybe you still have to write a software yo
urself.
But this kind of thing about writing software
is rare in modern
times, right?
Most people don't need to write their own software.
So what is the purpose of our program
design? The
important purpose is not to say that you
have to write a software
for yourself. The important purpose is
to learn
how to work with the computer, how the computer
is good at what kind of things, what
the computer can do, What kind of
thing is that computers are not easy to do or
are not good at doing.
So how does the computer generally solve the
problem?
For example, if we eat in a restaurant, just
sit down, I hope
to drink a glass of water, I
might say to Wetter, please give
me a glass of water.
Because this Viter is a
human, he is not a computer,
so just tell him, please
give me a glass of water.
Of course, it will know how to give you a
glass of water. He
will turn to the kitchen,
find a cup, pour a
glass of water for you,
and then bring it to you.
But for a computer, if you
want him to do something for you, it may
not be as good as automation. Maybe you need
to tell the computer how to do it step by
step, for example, you
might say to the rig. You have to turn
around and go to the
kitchen, then find a cup, then
find a kettle, then pour
some water into the cup, and finally
take the cup back to the table.
The computer is like this. In
fact, let’s say that he is a computer. He is
very smart and intelligent. In
fact, the computer will not do anything.
The computer will only do one
thing, that is, if you want it to be done
step by step, he will show you step by step.
Of course, what is his greatest
ability? You told him to
do this step, he will not
take that step, he will do everything you want
him
to do well, but he does not know how to string
these
steps to meet your
requirements, how to go Put these steps
together, this is what you do as a person
So when I face a person, we just
have to say what that person, what
do I want you to
do, and of course he knows what to do.
But in the face
of the computer, we have to
tell it how to
do, how to make this thing
When we want to tell the
computer, we want the computer to know how
to make a thing, we need
to have a certain way, we need
to have a certain means to describe this
step,
then this means is called a program
The program is a special programming language
to write a way to express how we want the
computer to solve the problem.
In other words, what is the role of programming
language? We use a programming language to tell
the computer, I want you to do it step by step,
how to go to the kitchen to get water to give me drink
So we are not using a programming language to
talk to a computer. We
use a programming language to write down the
steps to do things for the computer
and let the computer execute.
Conversation is another
thing. If we take a computer as a person,
what
is our conversation with the computer?
It’s
actually the actions you usually do on
your computer.
For example, if you see a piece of
software
on the desktop, you
want to attract him, you double click
Double click is the way you talk to him.
You are ordering it to do
things. Then he runs the
software and shows you the software
running. It is his feedback to you. This
is a conversation, but the
programming language
is not. Used to talk, you are not in
the process of compiling a language, not
in a programming language, he
makes a sentence,
this is not the same
What language does the computer
know? The computer actually only knows the
language on our
screen. What you see above is a series of
numbers. You may feel
strange. Is there a letter
here? That's right, this is a
hexadecimal
number, because there is a hexadecimal
number, that is, it
has a number from 0 to 15, each bit has
a number from 0 to 15, so the Arabic
number 0 to 9 is not enough. Expressed, we have
to
use the letters A to F to express the following
numbers,
so there will be letters inside,
but he is still a
number, this is a hexadecimal
number, this is a
This is a program that a computer can understand,
written in a language that the computer knows.
Obviously this program is
for you, and it is
in front of us. No
one can understand
it. I don't understand it. I don't
know what it means to be the CFFA.
Because
this piece of program is converted from
something
we can understand through
another piece of software, or through a
tool,
what he used to be like this
Of course, before you learn any programming
language, this paragraph may still be like
a book for you.
Although you can probably guess what kind
of things may be there, what
is this program doing? This program
is to use the 辗 division method to
calculate two numbers,
which is the greatest common divisor of
32 and 26 here.
So what you see is this program, although
this program is that we say that it is
written in human programming
language, but can you understand that
there is another thing on the
program, we are now listed on the left,
The series of texts listed on the right,
the text of this series,
we call it the algorithm, we
have to calculate the same
Things we need to have steps,
we have to tell the computer how to do it,
just like before going to the
water, we have to have a step by step step to
tell the computer, we
tell the computer that if you
find that one is already equal to 0, Then we
will finish the oil is the greatest common
divisor.
If V is not equal to 0,
we have to do a series of complicated calculations.
After we finish, we have to go back to the
first step, so that we can continue to
calculate and finally get a result.
Some of thes
So what you see in the computer is the kind of
binary stuff, and then
this is what the computer knows, right? Then
this is something
that people can understand, but this is
what programmers can understand. This is something
that people who have learned programming can understand.
On the Internet is something that ordinary people
can
understand. This is how to do the calculation,
that is, the algorithm.
There are many steps in the middle of everything from
algorithms
to programs to things that computers
can run. There are many things to do.
So we have to let the computer do the calculations,
we need to find the calculation steps like this,
and then the programmer will write it out.
Everything we do with a computer is called calculation. It is
not that only
addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division
are performed. Arithmetic operations are called
calculations. All things that are done by computers are calc
ulations.
Including calculating your
birthday, including drawing a
picture, including showing you a movie,
this is all calculations,
as long as the computer does things are calculations.
The calcula